<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Shivam Daryanani's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://shivamd.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://shivamd.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-11T14:24:54-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://shivamd.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Shivam Daryanani]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The world is ready for my thoughts.]]></title>
    <link href="http://shivamd.github.io/blog/2013/05/11/the-world-is-ready-for-my-thoughts/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-11T12:36:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://shivamd.github.io/blog/2013/05/11/the-world-is-ready-for-my-thoughts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I turned around to Stephane and said, &ldquo;I think the world is ready for my thoughts.&rdquo; He said, you mean you are ready to expose your thoughts to the world. I thought about that for a second, and realized how true that is. I have been wanting to start a blog since a year now, but I kept delaying it because I was afraid about what people might think. In reality nobody cares about you, all they think about is themselves.
Enough of that bullshit. I have finally reached a state of mind, where I don&rsquo;t mind putting myself out there.</p>

<h2>Tell me about Yourself.</h2>

<p>The interview question I dread.
Recently graduated from high school in Dubai. Wandered for a few months and initially decided to not follow the traditional path of college. Completed Dev Bootcamp, a 9 week intensive course on web development, on April 19th 2013. Currently an aspiring web developer. I love learning and exploring new things.
This is a brief overview of my journey over the past couple of years, read the whole account here.</p>

<p>My writings are going to be about the things I learn and my ramblings. Mainly about my journey as a software developer.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
